<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://boucheron.org/brian/</id>
  <link href="https://boucheron.org/brian/"/>
  <link href="https://boucheron.org/brian/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <title>Brian Boucheron</title>
  <updated>2018-02-28T05:13:03.929Z</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>First Cheddar Tasting</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2012/09/cheddar-tasting</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2012/09/cheddar-tasting"/>
    <updated>2012-09-25T09:32:00.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7819999662.jpg" alt="First Cheddar Tasting"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x2019;ve been sitting on these photos for about a month now, but somehow word still got out: the cheddar is open! I&amp;#x2019;ve already tasted or given away half the wheel, and the initial reviews are quite positive. I&amp;#x2019;m pretty happy with it myself. It tastes good, but maybe not perfect. Given that I was worried about it being a soaking moldy rancid mess when I finally cracked it open, I&amp;#x2019;m feeling pretty accomplished. It&amp;#x2019;s a bit moist&amp;#x2013;creamy even&amp;#x2013;and somewhat mild at this point in time (it&amp;#x2019;s about eight months old). It doesn&amp;#x2019;t seem to be oversalted. The curd is really well knit, with no gaps or crevices. It tastes a bit like a colby to me, so I have to figure out what the similarity is there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7819974674.jpg" alt="First Cheddar Tasting"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cut the wheel up into eights and vacuum packed them all. Hopefully I&amp;#x2019;ll be able to wait out the full year before tasting the rest, and we&amp;#x2019;ll see if it changes much in that time. In the meantime, the weather is getting nice and cool, and I&amp;#x2019;m finding myself in the kitchen more often on the weekends, cooking and baking and brewing. Hopefully the cheesemaking will resume in October, and I&amp;#x2019;ll be able to put up enough cheese over winter to satisfy the snacking appetite of family and friends for the next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7820045254.jpg" alt="First Cheddar Tasting"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Three Cheese Update</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2012/05/three-cheese-update</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2012/05/three-cheese-update"/>
    <updated>2012-05-21T18:55:23.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7005046138.jpg" alt="3 Week Provolone, Slicing"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first batch of provolone, having completed three weeks of hard labor in the cheese fridge, was ready for slicing and tasting last weekend. Hooray! After many requests for &amp;#x201C;some cheeses we can actually taste within the next year&amp;#x201D;, we now have some &lt;a href="http://boucheron.org/brian/2012/05/cream-cheesy-bagels"&gt;cream cheese&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://boucheron.org/brian/2012/04/fail-cheese"&gt;provolone&lt;/a&gt; in an edible state in the fridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheese is quite a pain to cut with a knife, and I don&amp;#x2019;t have any piano wire handy to make a wire-based cheese slicer, so I was quite happy to finally have a use for one of my hand cranked deli slicers, as you can see above. Don&amp;#x2019;t tell the hoarding police, but I have three of these things kicking around in the basement. The first one I dug up didn&amp;#x2019;t work so hot, but the one pictured above sliced the provolone beautifully. It has some squeaks and needs some cleaning and tuning, but in general it&amp;#x2019;s a lovely hunk of cast iron and it chewed through my two provolone lumps with ease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7151083301.jpg" alt="3 Week Provolone, Slicing"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7005069936.jpg" alt="3 Week Provolone, Slicing"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My parents scrounged me a vacuum sealer for Christmas last year, and this was its first use. I do hate the proliferation of plastic bags it encourages, but I suppose I hate freezer burn and wasted food moreso. The bags seem to be reusable though, so I&amp;#x2019;ll just be &amp;#x201C;that guy&amp;#x201D; who washes and dries items that are normally thought of as disposable. No matter&amp;#x2026; I hang laundry and prefer bikes to cars, so I&amp;#x2019;ve already been cast out of polite American society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7005092840.jpg" alt="VacuuProvolone"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vacuum sealer worked quite well, and by the end of this process I felt like a proper supermarketeer, with nicely sliced and plasticized cheeses, ready to be hung in the deli case next to the bologna and prosciutto (dangerously close to the liverwurst too, usually!). &lt;em&gt;Update: since writing this, we&amp;#x2019;ve broken into the provolone stash, and found all the slices had been vacuumed back into a single mass. Perhaps I will age provolone unsliced in the future.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now realize I&amp;#x2019;ve failed to mention something important: how did it taste?! I am relieved to report that it does indeed taste like provolone. Fairly mild at this point, but with a hint of sharp cheesiness. The rind is a bit drier and more pronounced than I&amp;#x2019;m used to. The humidity was a tad low in the cheese cave, so that may account for that. The texture inside seems about right, despite my problems stretching and forming the curd. Not sure what else to say&amp;#x2026; no doubt cheese mongers have a bounty of words used to describe cheese taste characteristics. Perhaps they&amp;#x2019;re even as varied and silly as those of wine aficionados&amp;#x2026; but for now, all I&amp;#x2019;ve got is: tastes cheesy, not spoiled, not too salty, A++ would ingest again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7005099026.jpg" alt="Parmesan, 3 Months"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I was already breaking out the vacuum-sealer-bot for long term provolone storage, I decided to quarter and pack my first parmesan and romano cheeses as well. One disadvantage of making wee little two pound cheeses is that the rind to insides ratio is all off compared to an 80 pound wheel. Unless you rub the rind with olive oil every once in a while, or wax your cheese, or vacuum pack it, you&amp;#x2019;ll end up with an overly dry, cracked up, 100% rindy cheese. No good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a bit worried I wouldn&amp;#x2019;t be able to cut the parmesan, due to my aforementioned lack of wire (not to mention the specialized knives usually used to split apart big wheels of parmesan), but my normal chef&amp;#x2019;s knife did the trick just fine. The romano was even easier, as it&amp;#x2019;s a bit more moist (probably &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; moist, actually). Both were quartered, and&amp;#x2013;after I snuck a taste&amp;#x2013;vacuum packed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, I have no good tasting notes&amp;#x2026; the parmesan seemed to have the right texture, a little crumbly and grainy. The taste was &amp;#x201C;getting there&amp;#x201D;. Not sharp, more salty than anything at this point. The romano was about the same, except not so dry, with no grainy texture. I almost want to compare the texture to muenster. I think it&amp;#x2019;s grate-able though, so it&amp;#x2019;ll probably work out. It certainly wont be drying out any more in the bag, so that&amp;#x2019;s possibly a mistake, but since you can eat it young as a table cheese anyways, I&amp;#x2019;m not too worried. Worst case we&amp;#x2019;ll eat the insides and grate the outsides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7005123366.jpg" alt="Romano, 3 Months"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7151224621.jpg" alt="CheeseBags"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that everything is all bagged up, my cheese cave is a bit boring. Besides the bags, I only have one wheel of waxed cheddar. Humidity in the cave isn&amp;#x2019;t so important now, but the temperature needs to remain at 50&amp;#x2013;55 degrees in order for everything age properly. So until I get a new cheese fridge up and running, the kegerator will remain a cheeserator. Sorry future party guests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that summer is upon us, I doubt I&amp;#x2019;ll want to spend hours in the kitchen with the stove on, so I might have to concentrate on quicker and easier cheese recipes. I&amp;#x2019;m thinking summer salads might need some crumbly blue cheeses involved, so perhaps I&amp;#x2019;ll make it my goal to get more acquainted with that particular mold in the very near future&amp;#x2026;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cream Cheesy Bagels</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2012/05/cream-cheesy-bagels</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2012/05/cream-cheesy-bagels"/>
    <updated>2012-05-04T21:32:00.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6984177282.jpg" alt="Cream Cheesemaking"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is something perversely satisfying about spending an excessive amount of time recreating commodity food items at home. I know I&amp;#x2019;m not alone in this affliction, as one of my favorite food blogs, &lt;a href="http://smittenkitchen.com/"&gt;Smitten Kitchen&lt;/a&gt;, seems to excel at making her own &lt;a href="http://smittenkitchen.com/2007/05/my-kingdom-for-a-glass-of-milk/"&gt;oreos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://smittenkitchen.com/2009/05/graham-crackers/"&gt;graham crackers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://smittenkitchen.com/2010/04/homemade-pop-tarts/"&gt;pop tarts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://smittenkitchen.com/2009/06/springy-fluffy-marshmallows/"&gt;marshmallows&lt;/a&gt;, and so on. Thus, having confirmed that I&amp;#x2019;m in good company, I decided to fritter away yet another Sunday in the kitchen, this time making cream cheese and bagels (sorry, no &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lox"&gt;lox&lt;/a&gt; (yet)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x2019;ll have to give bagel details at a later date, lest your eyeballs glaze before you make it to the glamor shots at the end of this post. If you simply cannot wait, I&amp;#x2019;ve got some photos of the bagel process in &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/sets/72157629958683315"&gt;my bread products Flickr set&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7129575059.jpg" alt="Cream Cheesemaking Fixins"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First step! Lay all your utensils and goodies on the counter in a neat and fussy arrangement. Get up on a stool and take pictures. Express thanks for a kitchen with a nice wood countertop right next to the lovely light of a large, north facing window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may notice the counter is pretty bare. Compared to the last time I made cheese, this is going to be relatively simple. Hooray!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7129597885.jpg" alt="Cream Heater"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step two: warm up the milky bits. I used half and half. You can probably use straight-up light cream, or even heavy cream if you&amp;#x2019;re a crazy cheese daredevil. Seventy-five degrees is your target. Precision isn&amp;#x2019;t terribly important here, we&amp;#x2019;re just trying to make the bacteria cozy, and they do tolerate a range of temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One slight complication: there&amp;#x2019;s a twelve hour long step coming up, so you&amp;#x2019;ll probably want to start this the night before and let your microbe friends work while you slumber. Plan ahead!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6983526554.jpg" alt="M E S O P H I L L I C"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;#x2019;re up to temperature, it&amp;#x2019;s time to add our bacterial culture. This comes as a packet of powder, which you keep in your freezer in order to prevent its inhabitants from waking up and hulking out in your pantry or other such inconvenient location. Snip the packet with the scissors you&amp;#x2019;ve previously sanitized (you sanitized all your equipment, right?), sprinkle it on top of the milk, and mix it in thoroughly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, here&amp;#x2019;s where my various cheese books disagree. Some of them tell you to add rennet as well. So, I did. I&amp;#x2019;m starting to think that&amp;#x2019;s unnecessary/cheating. The lactic acid produced by our bacteria should be able to curdle the milk on its own, given enough time. It sounds like the result would be lumpy curds floating in whey, instead of the uniform gel that I got, and I suspect that would be more authentic. I&amp;#x2019;ll try it the other way next time, if I&amp;#x2019;m feeling lucky and adventurous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6983553076.jpg" alt="Cozy Bath"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7129648699.jpg" alt="Cozy Bath"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, we now need to keep our pot o&amp;#x2019; milkstuff warm for twelve hours. In my yogurt making days I learned that a cooler and some warm water will keep things toasty for quite some time. So put your pot in a &amp;#x201C;cooler&amp;#x201D;, pour in some warm water, close the lid, call it a &amp;#x201C;warmer&amp;#x201D;, and go to bed. How much water to add&amp;#x2013;and at what temperature&amp;#x2013;is an experiment I&amp;#x2019;ll leave to you. I try to err towards more water at a not-too-hot temperature, so there&amp;#x2019;s enough thermal mass to last through the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this assumes that you&amp;#x2019;re not making cheese in a balmy climate. If you do happen to roost where &amp;#x201C;room temperature&amp;#x201D; is between seventy and eighty, just leave the pot out, taking appropriate precautions re: marauding cats and curious primates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7129660979.jpg" alt="14 Hours Later"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did these first steps at about five in the evening, so needless to say, twelve hours came and went before I rolled out of bed the next morning. No worries. I got to it at eight or so. Poking around in the pot with a washed finger revealed that our experiment had indeed firmed up overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7129668629.jpg" alt="Straining Tools"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7129674801.jpg" alt="Scoop and Strain"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step one million. Make yourself some tea, line a strainer with &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muslin"&gt;muslin&lt;/a&gt;, and grab an old-timey slotted spoon with a handle that&amp;#x2019;s quite likely covered in lead paint. Scoop and plop. Gather up the cloth to make a nice hobo sack (optional: contemplate &amp;#x201C;hobo cheese&amp;#x201D; for a bit), then hang it over a whey receptacle for about six hours while it drains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6983779534.jpg" alt="Hanging Cheese"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6983784162.jpg" alt="Hanging Cheese"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6983831330.jpg" alt="Hanging Cheese"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7130109221.jpg" alt="Six Hours Later"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there you have it. It should be firmed up and dried out a bit. Add some salt and you&amp;#x2019;re done. It&amp;#x2019;s never going to have the same texture as the cream cheese you get from the store, as it&amp;#x2019;s not full of odd gelling agents and fillers, but once you cool it down it&amp;#x2019;ll be nice and creamy and spreadable. It should last at least two weeks in the fridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or rather, it shouldn&amp;#x2019;t &lt;em&gt;spoil&lt;/em&gt; for at least two weeks. Whether it &lt;em&gt;lasts&lt;/em&gt; that long depends on how many bagels you have on hand. Out of a half gallon of half and half I ended up with about 1.8 pounds of cheese, or&amp;#x2013;at current rates of consumption&amp;#x2013;about two dozen bagels worth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7130120703.jpg" alt="Packaging"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7130233423.jpg" alt="Bagelmaking"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6984177282.jpg" alt="Cream Cheesemaking"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike all the other cheeses I&amp;#x2019;ve made so far, I&amp;#x2019;ve actually tasted this one! I think it came out really well. Pretty tangy and creamy. Maybe a little drier on the mouth than store-bought cream cheese, but at the same time a bit fresher and less gummy feeling. It&amp;#x2019;s probably not something I&amp;#x2019;d make terribly often (too many other cheeses to try!), but I&amp;#x2019;ll call it a success. It has certainly gotten good reviews in my limited test market of one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole process of making cream cheese reminded me of making a strained yogurt cheese, and indeed I&amp;#x2019;m feeling like the final result is quite similar (though a bit richer). Soon I&amp;#x2019;ll document the idiotically easy process of making said yogurt cheese, for those of you unwilling or unable to sacrifice so much time in pursuit of cultured dairy products.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Fail Cheese</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2012/04/fail-cheese</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2012/04/fail-cheese"/>
    <updated>2012-04-23T07:46:36.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7083694131.jpg" alt="The Fixins"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making cheese seemed like a pretty simple process when I laid out all the tools above. A pot, some spoons, milk, cultures, a thermometer, a knife to cut the curd. Of course, throughout the day I kept having to root around the kitchen for all the things I forgot to include: measuring spoons, a big stirring spoon (lots of spoons involved here, I&amp;#x2019;m noticing), a pH meter, all sorts of bowls, ice, twine, gloves, a whisk. Yeargh!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Sunday really turned into an annoying day in the kitchen. I started at around noon, and didn&amp;#x2019;t have cheeses in the brine pot until nine or ten that evening (much of this time is just spent waiting around for microbes or enzymes to do their thing, admittedly). On top of that, I messed it all up during the very last step, so I cleaned up and went to bed with a mild case of the grumps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh well. I&amp;#x2019;ll now step you through the process of making provolone, with too many pictures and too little explanation. It will look complicated (sortof) and time consuming (yup!), but if you&amp;#x2019;re interested in making cheese, there are many easier recipes you can start with (parmesean was really easy, if you don&amp;#x2019;t mind waiting six months to eat it), so don&amp;#x2019;t let the following mess dissuade you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6937628440.jpg" alt="Electronic Ignition"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7083710843.jpg" alt="Glug Glug Glug"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First step, sanitation! Every homebrewer&amp;#x2019;s favorite task, and just as important in cheesemaking. I gather all my utensils, and anything else that will touch the milk, and boil them for a bit. While that&amp;#x2019;s happening, I try to clean and scrub the entire kitchen as much as is practical, and then I kick everybody and everydog out of the room for the day. That always goes over well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the boil, I arrange my &amp;#x201C;clean zone&amp;#x201D; next to the stove, and fill the emptied pot with milk. I&amp;#x2019;ve been trying to get milk from the &lt;a href="http://www.cityofrochester.gov/publicmarket/"&gt;public market&lt;/a&gt; here in Rochester. &lt;a href="http://ilovenyfarms.com/about-us-other-brands"&gt;Some folks from Ithaca&lt;/a&gt; show up every week with yummy cream-top milk, so I get two gallons for whatever silly cheese I&amp;#x2019;m making that weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x2019;t have pictures of adding the cultures and the rennet. There&amp;#x2019;s not much to look at, as the milk just stubbornly continues to look like a pot of boring ol&amp;#x2019; milk. But, after bringing the milk up to ninety-seven degrees or so, you sprinkle in a powdered bacterial culture. This one was a buttermilk-ish type of culture. Others are more like yogurt. Their basic function at this point is to produce lactic acid&amp;#x2026; pH is really important throughout the cheesemaking process. This is intimidating to hobbyist cheesemakers, so most of the intro books completely ignore pH except when absolutely necessary, instead relying mostly on timing and crossed fingers to get things right. It seems to work out, usually, so no worries there (for now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the bacteria drops the pH a bit, we add in the rennet. This is the enzyme that actually curdles the milk. Stir it in, and then go relax for a bit. Forty minutes maybe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6937642122.jpg" alt="Clean Break"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6937647336.jpg" alt="Cutting Curd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wash your hands and give the curd a bit of a pokey-scoop with your index finger. If it looks like the picture above, you&amp;#x2019;ve got a &amp;#x201C;clean break&amp;#x201D; and you&amp;#x2019;re ready to cut your curd. I use a knife that I believe is designed for cutting roasts. It works well enough. Of course there are specialized curd knives&amp;#x2026; but you could probably even just use a long thin metal frosting spreader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal here was to cut three-eighth inch cubes of curd. Getting your curd sizes even is pretty important (it&amp;#x2019;s mainly a moisture thing), and I fail at it every time. Things still work out well, but it&amp;#x2019;s something I definitely have to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After cutting, the curds rest a bit. They are delicate little things at this point, and giving them a break lets them start to firm up before we jiggle them around with our stirring. Failing to do so could result in us bashing precious milkfat out of the curd structure and into the whey. Your whey should be a clear yellowish-green color, and if it&amp;#x2019;s clouded up, that means you&amp;#x2019;re guilty of curd abuse. Sinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7083727149.jpg" alt="Stirring Curd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we can stir! We raise the temperature up &lt;em&gt;vewwwy vewwwy&lt;/em&gt; slowly (half a degree per minute in this case) while stirring with some regularity. Our goal is to expel more and more moisture from inside the curds. Going too fast can result in a &amp;#x201C;rind&amp;#x201D; of sorts forming on the curds, which would trap moisture in the interior. No good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6937670152.jpg" alt="Draining Curd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6937674692.jpg" alt="Water Bath"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7083753687.jpg" alt="Acidification"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having heated, stirred, rested, et cetera, we now drain the curd, seperating it from the whey (which we reserve for use as a brine later, though normally I would feed it to my imaginary pigs). It is then put back in the pot and held at 104 degrees or so for hours. The main goal at this stage is acidification, although we&amp;#x2019;re also expelling more and more water from the curd. In the case of provolone, mozzerella, and other stretched curd cheeses, pH is extra critical, as it is a big factor regarding whether the curd will stretch or not (it also heavily affects meltability).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I failed to document myself fumbling around with the pH meter. It probably took four hours for the curd to drop down to pH 5.2 and thus be ready for the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7083758665.jpg" alt="Draining Again"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7083775417.jpg" alt="Cutting Curd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drain your curd. Again. Then cut it up into cubes. We&amp;#x2019;re now ready to heat these cubes up and mush and stretch and pull them. Unfortunely, in this case, we&amp;#x2019;re also at the step where I totally failed. Well, not totally. &lt;em&gt;Mostly&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7083792153.jpg" alt="Mushing Curd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6937721750.jpg" alt="Stretching Curd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The curd cubes go in a bowl, and hot whey or water is poured over them. We need to get the curd up to 170 or 180 degrees. This was my problem, I think. My whey was hot enough, but I don&amp;#x2019;t think the curd ever got up to the right temperature. I had bits that were stretching well, interspersed with unstretchy bits. At the time I thought my pH was off and I just soldiered on. In hindsight, I should&amp;#x2019;ve put the whole gloppy mess back on the stove until the curd came up to temperature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh well. I stretched as best I could. You&amp;#x2019;re supposed to pull it out two or three times like you&amp;#x2019;re making saltwater taffy (because, you know, everybody has done &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt;, right?). Meanwhile, you&amp;#x2019;re wrist-deep in 180 degree whey, and your stupid &lt;em&gt;Good Housekeeping&lt;/em&gt; approved neoprene gloves are not quite as insulative as you had hoped. And you didn&amp;#x2019;t take off your stupid thermal before starting, so you&amp;#x2019;re frustrated and hot and you spent nine hours making two pounds of this stupid fail cheese you&amp;#x2019;re such an idiot&amp;#x2026;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6937733300.jpg" alt="Shaping Curd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2026;&lt;em&gt;aaaand&lt;/em&gt; deep breath. And relax. That doesn&amp;#x2019;t look so bad now. After streching a few times, you shape it into a ball or two, or a sausage shape, or a &amp;#x201C;jug&amp;#x201D; shape, or a gourd shape. Apparently provolone can be whatever the heck shape you want it to be, so that&amp;#x2019;s exciting. Next time I&amp;#x2019;ll be sure to make a mobius strip or a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Klein_bottle"&gt;klein bottle&lt;/a&gt;. This time around I made a ball, and a &amp;#x201C;jug&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6937738900.jpg" alt="A Nice Curdball"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7083847309.jpg" alt="Preserved Specimen"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of my aformentioned problems, not only didn&amp;#x2019;t the curd stretch well, but it also didn&amp;#x2019;t knit back together so hot. You can see on one side it seems like a smooth and shiny ball, but on the other side&amp;#x2013;let&amp;#x2019;s call it &amp;#x201C;the butt&amp;#x201D;&amp;#x2013;it simply wouldn&amp;#x2019;t gather back up into a smooth surface. I&amp;#x2019;ve got tons of cracks and crevices in both cheeses because of this. Surely these will cause me mold and cracking issues during aging. I think we&amp;#x2019;ll eat these as fresh as possible in about three weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cheese above that looks like a lab specimen is actually floating in an icewater bath. You need to cool down your hot cheese in order to firm it up in whatever dysfunctional shape you&amp;#x2019;ve massaged it into. After doing so, we make a brine out of the reserved whey and some kosher salt, cool it to cheese cave temperatures (fifty-five degrees), and let the cheeses sit in it for a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7083857655.jpg" alt="Brine Dunktank"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7083864657.jpg" alt="24 Hour Nap"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6940001326.jpg" alt="Hanging Cheeses"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, twine it somehow, and hang it in a fifty to fifty-five degree fridgecave for three weeks. After that, you can eat it right away or age it for up to a year under more typical fridge temperatures. You can also smoke provolone pretty successfully, but I&amp;#x2019;ve decided to cut my losses and put no further effort into these particular cheeses. Maybe next time. Just remember you&amp;#x2019;ll need to &lt;em&gt;cold&lt;/em&gt; smoke them, otherwise you&amp;#x2019;d end up with a delicious provolone puddle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#x2019;s that. Believe it or not, there are more pictures in &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/sets/72157628911833001/"&gt;my cheesemaking set on Flickr&lt;/a&gt;, if you&amp;#x2019;ve not had enough already. And stay tuned for more cheesemaking adventures, because nothing says &amp;#x201C;summer&amp;#x201D; like spending the weekend inside, standing over a hot stove. Yay!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Making Cheese</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2012/03/making-cheese</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2012/03/making-cheese"/>
    <updated>2012-03-31T12:44:26.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7030390405.jpg" alt="Cheese Updates"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x2019;ve been making cheese a bit lately, and that&amp;#x2019;s somewhat interesting I think, so I decided to dust off the ol&amp;#x2019; blog and camera for proper documentation and dissemination. You can find more photos of the actual making of these cheeses at my &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bert_m_b/sets/72157628911833001"&gt;cheesemaking photoset on Flickr&lt;/a&gt;, and I promise to be more proactive next time I spend a Sunday in the kitchen, stirring curds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, why the heck did I start making cheese at home? Who knows. I like to make things that have to age for years before I can eat or drink them, and I enjoy making foods that involve bacteria, fungi, or yeasts. I&amp;#x2019;m sure some of my interest was also stimulated by the summer I spent milking goats (check the scrollback for more on that). Any way you slice it, for some reason I bought a book called &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/H8AvWQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Home Cheesemaking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="http://www.cheesemaking.com/"&gt;Ricki Carroll&lt;/a&gt;, and I flipped through it really quick, and then it sat in the book pile next to my bed for about a year, slowly creeping its way towards the floor as other books became a higher priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally dusted it off this January and decided to make cheddar, and thus began three straight weekends of kitchen toil. I bought some rennet and cultures from &lt;a href="http://www.cheesemaking.com/"&gt;Ricki Carroll&amp;#x2019;s site&lt;/a&gt; (this reminds me, I &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; try making cheese a few years ago, using grocery store rennet, but it turned out pretty terrible, so I guess I purged it from memory). I then made a special trip to the public market, hoping to get some good milk from the Ithaca dairy guy that usually attends, but alas, he was not there. I was more successful at the &lt;a href="http://www.abundance.coop/"&gt;hippy food co-op&lt;/a&gt;, where I believe they carry the very same milk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was a Saturday morning. I then spent the rest of the day mentally preparing by reading and rereading the recipe (no, really (I do this a lot)), and gathering the equipment I&amp;#x2019;d need to perform this feat. The next day was a long day of cleaning the kitchen, cleaning it more, cleaning utensils and pots and pans, and then the precise heating of milk, along with additions of cultures and rennet and lots of waiting for said items to do their magic. I probably spent six or eight hours creating the cheddar. The other cheeses were easier and quicker. Again, next time I&amp;#x2019;ll document better and give you a bit more of a step by step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7030417163.jpg" alt="The Cheese Cave"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#x2019;s the thousand foot overview. The next weekend I made parmesan. And after that, romano. I needed a place to age these. Above, you&amp;#x2019;ll see my kegerator, which was a free find on craigslist (woohoo!). Since I don&amp;#x2019;t make beer often enough anymore, the kegerator has turned into a trusty cheeserator (ahem: &amp;#x201C;cheese cave&amp;#x201D;), providing roughly the right environment for turning new cheese into old cheese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7030420739.jpg" alt="The Cheese Cave, Interior"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6884324862.jpg" alt="The Cheese Cave, Interior"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With any luck, I&amp;#x2019;ll need more shelves in there soon, but for a quick retrofit it works pretty well. That&amp;#x2019;s a cutting board resting on top of some canning jars to keep it out of any moisture that might collect on the floor of the fridge. The thermostat on the fridge didn&amp;#x2019;t mind going up to fifty-five degrees, so I thankfully didn&amp;#x2019;t need to go get an external temperature controller ($$$). The humidity seems to want to be at 75% or so (that&amp;#x2019;d make a good humidor, I hear), so a pan of water or two does a good job of bringing it up to the 80&amp;#x2013;85% that I&amp;#x2019;m looking for. I&amp;#x2019;ve been running it a little dry lately to keep the mold at bay, but in doing so I&amp;#x2019;m risking some cracking of the cheeses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some day I&amp;#x2019;ll wire up a hygrometer and humidifier with some overengineered elctronics for more precise control over this particular variable. In the meantime, I&amp;#x2019;ll reflect upon some frequent advice from the homebrewing world: &amp;#x201C;relax, don&amp;#x2019;t worry, and have a homebrew&amp;#x201D;. I&amp;#x2019;m sure it&amp;#x2019;ll all work out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7030365459.jpg" alt="Cheese Updates"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the parmesan, cheese #2. It&amp;#x2019;s about one and a half pounds, and two months old. In a few weeks, I&amp;#x2019;ll probably rub it with olive oil to keep the rind from cracking, or I might bag it up and vacuum seal it. I haven&amp;#x2019;t decided yet. I do like the idea of natural rinds, full of texture and mold and &amp;#x201C;character&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/7030380279.jpg" alt="Cheese Updates"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6884298954.jpg" alt="Cheese Updates"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romano! It had a bit more yield than the parmesan, probably two pounds. Of course it&amp;#x2019;s also softer/wetter, so I&amp;#x2019;m sure most of that is water weight. It&amp;#x2019;s drying and aging nicely. I could probably slice it up and eat it soft in a few months, but I&amp;#x2019;m planning to dry it right out for a nice grating cheese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/6884286378.jpg" alt="Cheese Updates"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&amp;#x2019;s the first cheese I made&amp;#x2026; good ol&amp;#x2019; cheddar (obviously this one has been waxed, next time I may try a natural rind of some sort). There are many ways to take shortcuts making cheddar. They all involve trying to avoid the two or three hour process of cheddaring, which basically consists of holding slabs of curd at a specific temperature while they expel whey and acidify. The curds require some tending during the process, so it definitely made for a long day in the kitchen. But, I wanted to try the &amp;#x201C;real&amp;#x201D; way at least once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now I continue to wait for these cheeses to age. They&amp;#x2019;ll all be tasty around a year from now, but I might slip up and sample them a bit earlier. I guess that depends on if I get down to making some fresher, less aged cheeses to tide me over in the meantime. For obvious reasons, I&amp;#x2019;ve been searching around for a good &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bucheron"&gt;bucheron&lt;/a&gt; cheese recipe for a while now. Bucheron is a ripened goat cheese. Basically a chevre with a bloomy (white mold) rind that you age for four weeks or so. It&amp;#x2019;s really really tasty (I&amp;#x2019;m so glad my namesake cheese is so yummy!). I finally found a recipe for it in the second cheese book I bought, &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/HACpt9"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artisan Cheesemaking at Home&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. There&amp;#x2019;s actually lots of neat and creative recipes in there&amp;#x2026; cheeses you&amp;#x2019;ll not be finding in the grocery store any time soon, so stay tuned for updates on those (and if you&amp;#x2019;re in Rochester, or on my Christmas list, maybe you&amp;#x2019;ll even get to taste some)!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Transitional Species</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2008/08/transitional-species</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2008/08/transitional-species"/>
    <updated>2008-08-31T12:00:06.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2704218284.jpg" alt="Guinea Fowl, Two Weeks"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well. I find myself missing the above pictured critters, as well as
the goats, oxen, yaks, and farm folk. I left the farm mid-August,
in order to get home and take care of some pressing matters. I
guess things were getting pretty routine by that point anyway, and
it made me itch to get home and start doing something&amp;#x2026; finding
some land, developing some freelance work, learning some
newly-important life skills, working on some different farms. I&amp;#x2019;m
not sure what I&amp;#x2019;ll have to blabber about on the blog now, but you
should be warned that some of it will probably be 1000% more nerdy
than before. We&amp;#x2019;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right after I got home, Rachel and I zipped off to Maine to laze
about for a week at her parents&amp;#x2019; place. That certainly delayed my
settling-in phase here in Rochester, but made for a great
transition between two very different worlds. I still get up fairly
early, but I am creeping later and later each day, and I stay up
too late. I&amp;#x2019;ll have to work on that, as I enjoy getting up at six
and having the quiet morning to myself. Also, it is odd to have too
much free time and too little hard labor. I&amp;#x2019;ve contacted some local
farms and hopefully will find a place I can visit and work at
between my job and freelance and other pursuits&amp;#x2026; the garden just
doesn&amp;#x2019;t cut it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2810083764.jpg" alt="Birthday Cake Fire"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We happened to be in Maine on my birthday, and Rachel &amp;amp; her sister
made me a yummy farm-themed cake. They managed to cover all the
important animals from the farm, except the yaks. There was even a
team of appropriately colored oxen, munching on the coconut and
frosting &amp;#x201C;grass&amp;#x201D;. I managed to milk the birthday event for almost a
full week&amp;#x2026; eating too much, drinking vast quantities of yummy
beer, and lazing about reading books and taking naps. Whee!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2809268799.jpg" alt="Birthday Brace Balloon"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now it&amp;#x2019;s back to reality-land. First on the to-do list was to
set up an office here at Rachel&amp;#x2019;s place, which I guess is now &amp;#x201C;our
place&amp;#x201D;. Having done that I am now ready to dive into some freelance
work, and have indeed already talked to the bike shop and started
some materials for next year&amp;#x2019;s Tour de New York (the first, I
suppose). Soon I will return to my prior job part-time as well, and
also try to work in some internships, with any luck. So maybe there
will soon be more variety here, instead of all these tiresome
pictures of farm animals! Who knows!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Garlic Harvest</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2008/07/garlic-harvest</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2008/07/garlic-harvest"/>
    <updated>2008-07-17T20:45:21.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2675697716.jpg" alt="Visitor, From Another Planet"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had visitors last weekend. Somehow only one of them managed to
get photographed. Rachel drove to Rome, and hitched a ride the rest
of the way with my parents, who were on their way to Vermont to
meet up with other Volkswagen Bus weirdos. So they got in fairly
early on Friday, and we put her to work rather quickly after the
folks left. For some reason we were a little behind in the harvest.
Oh yeah&amp;#x2026; because a goat had a broken leg and there were vet
visits and such to worry about. So Rachel and I harvested together
whilst everybody else was off at the vet. We bunched up kale,
beets, carrots, and lots of herbs. Probably some other stuff I&amp;#x2019;ve
forgotten about as well. (Oh yeah! Two kinds of cucumbers and three
squashies.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it was nice to see her, and even though we couldn&amp;#x2019;t manage to
chit-chat while harvesting and counting bunches and such, it was a
nice plump weekend of activities. Too much walking to town and back
though&amp;#x2026; I was getting more tired on my days off than during the
week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2674880635.jpg" alt="Shelburne Falls Potholes"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took a short ride to Shelburne Falls, and wandered around there
like touristy folk. There is a bridge of flowers that we walked
along, with Rachel telling me what they all were and me forgetting
them promptly. It was quite lovely, and I managed to take zero
pictures. We got a frozen hot chocolate at a cafe, and it was
delicious and not at all like a chocolate milkshake thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parents came back Sunday evening, and we went out to dinner at
a local bar, of which I didn&amp;#x2019;t get the impression of &amp;#x201C;fine
eatery&amp;#x201D;&amp;#x2026; but it was really quite good. I made everybody eat some
mussels. And the desserts were fantastic looking, so we were all
fatty-fats and pigged out. Then we came back and drank some beer
and played pitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2674899563.jpg" alt="Garlic Buggie"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, everybody left me on Monday. Poo. Then it was back to the
same old. Wednesday was a little different though&amp;#x2026; we harvested
all the garlic. Not sure how much, we never did end up counting
bulbs. It was about fifty pounds of seed garlic though. So we
pulled it all up, laid it out, filled up a cart, dragged it to the
barn, bunched it up, and hung it on strings. It was kindof my first
blister-causing activity. My hands are a mess, which made it hard
to weed and trellis tomatoes today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2674902803.jpg" alt="Garlic Pile"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2675731830.jpg" alt="Garlic Harvest"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It smells rather delicious walking through the barn now&amp;#x2026; and of
course I&amp;#x2019;m making some hilarious vampire jokes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2674908369.jpg" alt="Guinea Fowl, One Week"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wee Guinea Fowl are one week closer to ugliness. Look at that
elongating neck! They&amp;#x2019;ve been moved inside with their surrogate
mother. Now they reside in an old playpen, and thankfully still
make only cute chick sounds. I anticipate they&amp;#x2019;ll be out and about
before they learn how to be more obnoxious. I wonder, will they act
somewhat more chickenish then the other Guineas? Will they all get
along? Probably not&amp;#x2026; they&amp;#x2019;re known for finding at least one of
their own to pick on and excommunicate. Heartless poultry. I think
I shall eat one of you after all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Baby Noisemakers</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2008/07/baby-noisemakers</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2008/07/baby-noisemakers"/>
    <updated>2008-07-09T21:36:10.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Spring is long gone, yet we have some new babies on the farm, as of
yesterday. We&amp;#x2019;ve had some guinea fowl eggs stuck underneath a
broody hen (chicken) for what seems like months now (probably four
weeks really)&amp;#x2026; so I decided to poke around underneath her and see
if there was any activity. There was!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2650836611.jpg" alt="Guinea Hatch"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may be able to see, I discovered a guinea chick peeping
around underneath the hen. Broody Hen (that&amp;#x2019;s what we&amp;#x2019;ve taken to
calling her) quickly got used to everybody poking around underneath
her to get a look, and now doesn&amp;#x2019;t even peck at you as you root
around under her warm blobby broody body. The chicks are up and
about today, pecking at some mash and getting wee baby drinks of
water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2653365479.jpg" alt="Guinea Daylings"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2654191132.jpg" alt="Guinea Daylings"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#x2019;s what passes for excitement around here. Entertainment,
really. I realize I may have spoken poorly of the guineas in the
past, but they&amp;#x2019;ve really grown on me this summer. They eat a lot of
ticks, and don&amp;#x2019;t eat the vegetables in the garden. They run much
faster and more elegantly than the fat chickens, have some level of
personality (mostly &amp;#x201C;stupid&amp;#x201D;), and roam far and wide on the
property, often stopping traffic in the road and exploring the
neighbor&amp;#x2019;s yards. Plus, they can actually fly a little bit, yet
choose to stick around and roost in our half-dead apple tree. How
sweet. So in summary, I&amp;#x2019;m happy we&amp;#x2019;re growing up two more, and I
hope they make it and I probably wont even try to slaughter them
and bring them back to Rochester in freezer bags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, we&amp;#x2019;re catching up with our weeding, sortof. It was a
long day in the tomato patch today, and my grab, twist, and pull
muscles are tired. I reserved enough strength to do the evening
milking, and now I get a rest. I suspect tomorrow will involve some
weeding of the melon beds. And the winter squash. And the corn. And
the pumpkins. Blah. It is rather hot and humid here, and today I
considered becoming one of those people who complains about the
weather (a retiree?)&amp;#x2026; but, anything under ninety and I refuse to
change out of my work pants and into shorts&amp;#x2026; so no bellyaching.
There was a nice breeze today, but apparently not at ground level.
The trees whooshed and swooshed, yet there was stillness down in
the weeds. Hot days make me wear sunscreen. Obviously that&amp;#x2019;s
stupid, as the quantity of solar radiation apparently has no
bearing on my application, just warmth. I guess it correlates
pretty well. I&amp;#x2019;m rather tanned, but still feel I could get pinky
after a long day in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x2019;m babbling. It is time to shut in the chickens and chicks, and
then head to bed. Much visitor preparation is needed tomorrow,
along with weeding and laundry and on and on.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Status Report</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2008/07/status-report</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2008/07/status-report"/>
    <updated>2008-07-06T22:01:58.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2643895200.jpg" alt="Misty Night"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose a little bit has happened since our last chat. There have
been a lot of harvests, a lot of markets, and a lot of weeding.
Blech. We&amp;#x2019;ve finally moved on from just greens, with some beets and
carrots and squash now showing up on our market tables. That feels
nice. I&amp;#x2019;m not sick of salads, but will enjoy the added variety
nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x2019;ve also blown through all of our garlic scapes in the past few
weeks. What a lovely product. Waste product is more like it, as we
would cut them off even if nobody were willing to buy them. But
people do, and as they should because it&amp;#x2019;s quite the nice delicate
garlic taste right when everybody&amp;#x2019;s garlic braids are running out
from the previous season. Soon we will start harvesting fresh
garlic for the CSA, and then I&amp;#x2019;ll get to see how we harvest and dry
the rest, and perhaps even try my hand at making some braids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had visitors, many weeks ago. My parents came out for a few days
in their Vanagon&amp;#x2026; and they dragged Rachel along for the ride. In
fact, they will be doing the very same thing next weekend on their
way to Vermont for some crazy Volkswagen meet-up they seem to be
attending yearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2586001266.jpg" alt="Grain Mill"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2585207649.jpg" alt="Stout Fermentation"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2586089082.jpg" alt="Bottling"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went on a tour of the &lt;a href="http://www.berkshirebrewingcompany.com/"&gt;Berkshire Brewing Company&lt;/a&gt; while they
were in town. It was quite the nice tour, with an ample amount of
free tastings and an entertaining tour guide&amp;#x2026; rather in depth and
fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the folks had a good time here at the farm. They brought
plenty of beer and crackers and cheese and Rachel and I helped them
consume it whilst playing Pitch around the wee table in their
camper. Mom hopefully got enough pampering in, bringing fixings for
dinner and breakfast and also some cookies and the like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2587848450.jpg" alt="Experimental Casks"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2585959648.jpg" alt="Tasting Room"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also went out to a flea market, which was not quite a bust, but
close. We showed up late due to poor directions, and it was a
semi-cloudy-rainy day anyways, so people were packing up and
heading home. I got a good camera tripod though, so that&amp;#x2019;s good.
And afterwards there happened to be a good brewpub on the way home,
so we stopped there for a late lunch. You can perhaps see a theme
developing here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2643073087.jpg" alt="Northeastern Permaculture Convergence, Summer 2008"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2643101969.jpg" alt="Northeastern Permaculture Convergence, Summer 2008"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2643965964.jpg" alt="Northeastern Permaculture Convergence, Summer 2008"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2643951042.jpg" alt="Northeastern Permaculture Convergence, Summer 2008"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past weekend I went to the Northeastern Permaculture
Convergence in Holyoke. I haven&amp;#x2019;t got the brain capacity right now
to explain what permaculture is&amp;#x2026; perhaps someday. But it&amp;#x2019;s
somewhat involved in designing agricultural systems, if you will.
Anyways, it was an interesting weekend, and I&amp;#x2019;m still processing
things in my head. I met Dave from Rochester there, who has
&lt;a href="http://www.greenerminds.com/"&gt;a blog&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;#x2019;ve been reading for a while now. So that made it
pretty worthwhile. We didn&amp;#x2019;t talk a ton, but he seemed great and
will no doubt be a valuable resource upon my return. He has some
connections within organizations I&amp;#x2019;m interested in, and also is
tinkering with his own permaculture garden/yard which I hope to
view someday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess there were around 100 other people at the convergence. I
didn&amp;#x2019;t talk to many of them. I&amp;#x2019;m antisocial, and suck at events
such as this. But I did meet a lot of nice folks, and picked a few
brains. Mainly I enjoyed touring some farms, gardens, and
nurseries. Of course I didn&amp;#x2019;t write down the scores of cool plants
I saw, but I feel like I&amp;#x2019;m not at that stage yet, and have the
names of some books to obtain that should point out the highlights
at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2643162131.jpg" alt="Northeastern Permaculture Convergence, Summer 2008"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2644004548.jpg" alt="Northeastern Permaculture Convergence, Summer 2008"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2643180909.jpg" alt="Northeastern Permaculture Convergence, Summer 2008"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it feels good to be back at the farm. Things were a little
weird when I got back, with the oxen getting out of their pasture
once again, apparently a problem all weekend. That&amp;#x2019;s pretty
frustrating. And there are many animals that need moving in the
morning, which I don&amp;#x2019;t entirely look forward to. But. Being away
made me appreciate many more things about this place, so I shall
not complain.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Misty Morning</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2008/06/misty-morning</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2008/06/misty-morning"/>
    <updated>2008-06-08T20:28:42.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2562453316.jpg" alt="Good Morning Farm"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been rather warm and moist here lately. I woke up today
(Sunday, my &amp;#x201C;day off&amp;#x201D;) at around five, with the sun peeking in the
hayloft doors (which are now permanently open to ventilate the goat
butt barn scent). I&amp;#x2019;m not sure what compelled me to bound out of
bed and take pictures. Perhaps my lack of doing so for the past two
weeks. Or perhaps because the sun had a particular hazy, diffuse
quality that I knew would be gone pretty quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So off I went. It was my first t-shirt-only morning&amp;#x2026; plus muck
boots, dress pants, suspenders, and my camera bag. I guess I got
some ok shots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, the point of all this was that it is rather pretty here,
I&amp;#x2019;ve found. Yesterday after the market I took some detours on my
bike ride back. Various dirt roads deep into dark dark woods
smelling slightly acidic and decayed. Some were shortcuts between
more civilized roads. Some went beyond my means of locomotion, with
steep descents that I didn&amp;#x2019;t feel like tackling in the opposite
direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were lots of hills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was all quiet and beautiful, with woods and cows and barns and
fields and streams and gardens and an old round brick schoolhouse
and a beehive on somebody&amp;#x2019;s porch roof (bearproofing, I suppose)
and hills and valleys and misty bits and clotheslines and nice
views and nice smells. I will have to do more exploring, at more
photogenic times of day and with my camera on board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2561639437.jpg" alt="Good Morning Farm"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this mist and haze is, unfortunately, because it is durn hot
here. Only low nineties really, but it doesn&amp;#x2019;t feel nice. We went
from steady rain and a flood warning Thursday night and Friday
morning (when I got soaked through my &amp;#x201C;rain suit&amp;#x201D; while moving the
sheep) to the nineties on Saturday, and through the next few days
it seems. Last night was quite interesting, clear skies overhead
and clouds with silent lightning off in the distance (I guess you
may call it heat lightning, but it&amp;#x2019;s really just a normal storm you
can&amp;#x2019;t hear due to distance or refraction of sound waves (says
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heat_lightning"&gt;the internets&lt;/a&gt;), so let us just call it lightning, ok?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In wildlife news, I saw a black bear a few nights ago, with two
cubs close behind. They were basically at the tree line you can see
in the pictures above&amp;#x2026; which is rather too close to where we have
the boy sheep currently. They freaked out a bit. Doggie inspection
revealed no bears in the woods shortly after I spotted them, so
maybe they were just passing through for a dip in the stream
(something that has crossed my mind recently).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derek found the guinea hen&amp;#x2019;s nest, with something like twenty eggs
piled up in there. A few were placed underneath the broody chicken
hen in the coop, so we&amp;#x2019;ll see if anything hatches. I guess most
people will remove the eggs and store them until the hen is ready
to sit for a while&amp;#x2026; because they don&amp;#x2019;t start sitting until
they&amp;#x2019;ve got them all out. I guess that makes sense. I&amp;#x2019;ve taken to
liking the guineas, even though they&amp;#x2019;re obnoxiously loud. They
don&amp;#x2019;t eat the crops and keep me from getting ticks. They can stay
for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>First Market</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2008/05/first-market</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2008/05/first-market"/>
    <updated>2008-05-26T21:51:36.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2519267024.jpg" alt="Harvest"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Friday was our first harvest day, in preparation for the
Ashfield Farmer&amp;#x2019;s Market Saturday morning. It was pretty exciting
to finally be able to snip some edible bits off of some of the
plants we&amp;#x2019;ve been staring at for more than a month now. We mostly
had salad mix and spinach from the beds in the greenhouse. I
remember preparing some of those beds my first weekend here, back
in April. It feels like everything is growing sooooo slooooowly,
but I think I just have unrealistic expectations. It sure is nice
though, to sit up in the barn loft and look at the fields, with
rows upon rows of thin green lines (some red and purple)&amp;#x2026; I can&amp;#x2019;t
wait until they&amp;#x2019;re all thick green lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2519274634.jpg" alt="Trimmings"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2519271560.jpg" alt="Harvest"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also pulled up some onions that had overwintered in the field
across the road. Their existence wasn&amp;#x2019;t really intentional: it was
a bed that had been lost to weeds last year and mowed down to
nothing before winter. But they came back, and upon pulling them up
they had some nice white bulbs attached. So we made up about 35
bunches of those, which involved cleaning off the gunky layers,
snipping the roots, bunching them up, and washing them off in a
bucket. A lot of labor, but worth it because nobody else had fresh
onions at the market. Rounding out the selection was bunches of
chives, a few bunches of tarragon, and that&amp;#x2019;s it. All of this was
packed up and ready for the CSA members to pick up at the market.
We don&amp;#x2019;t divvy things out into boxes and drop them off anywhere,
instead our members get a canvas bag with a pretty Sangha Farm logo
on it, and they just come to the market and fill it up. It
certainly makes things easier on us, and I think is good for the
customer, as they can pick and choose only the things they want
(although there is something to be said for being forced to try the
new fruits and vegetables you find in your CSA share).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2518464003.jpg" alt="Packing Up"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2518473585.jpg" alt="Setting Up"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2519161331.jpg" alt="Ashfield Farmer&amp;apos;s Market"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to our meager selection of produce, we had a ton of
vegetable starts to bring to the market. The van was quite full,
with multiple tiers of precariously stacked flats of delicate
plants. Luckily the market is only about one mile away. We got
there at seven and were just finishing setup by eight thirty when
the market opens. As of right now us interns don&amp;#x2019;t really have to
work the market, so after hanging around and helping out a little
bit, I wandered off and sat under a tree to write letters. It was a
beautiful day, and tons of people came out. The market is much
smaller than Rochester&amp;#x2019;s main public market, and much more social.
In the center of all the tents was a constant four hour meeting of
neighbors and friends (and dogs). A man in a bowler hat and bow tie
came and played cello for a bit. Another man brought two tiny
donkeys and walked them around while being followed by eager
donkey-petters (they were amazingly soft (the donkeys)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After writing letters for a while, I wandered to the post office
and the hardware store, and got back in time to see the ice cream
truck pull up in front of the town green where the market is held.
It&amp;#x2019;s an old converted school bus, out of which is served locally
made organic ice cream. Of course I had to sample some, and indeed
the butter pecan was quite delicious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ooh! I forgot about the cheese. We finally got our license to make
and sell cheese. What an amazingly bureaucratic process that is.
I&amp;#x2019;m sure I didn&amp;#x2019;t even really hear about half of it, but from what
I did hear it&amp;#x2019;s no wonder there are very few small-time dairies
around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, we made it through all the hoops, and Maribeth cranked out as
much cheese as possible before the market. She had a sample tray
all set up and received many complements and sold out of everything
she made. That means there will be two more does joining us, and
the two does with kids still nursing will be separated at night so
we can steal the morning milk at least. More milk! Unfamiliar
teats! Yikes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2519301840.jpg" alt="Wee Donkey"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2519296788.jpg" alt="Town Hall"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Visitor From Another World</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2008/05/visitor-from-another-world</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2008/05/visitor-from-another-world"/>
    <updated>2008-05-21T22:03:28.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Ack! It&amp;#x2019;s already Wednesday night and I haven&amp;#x2019;t written about last
week or this past weekend even! Even now, at nine o&amp;#x2019;clock, I feel
bad because my typing is probably keeping Adam up, and really I
would enjoy sleeping very much. We&amp;#x2019;ve shifted our schedule around,
so now I&amp;#x2019;m getting up at five thirty, eating breakfast and
attempting to slowly start the day, and then out and working by
seven. I guess that&amp;#x2019;s not crazy early. It feels it though,
especially when you have to milk in the evening and aren&amp;#x2019;t really
done working until eight thirty. I&amp;#x2019;ve taken to making lunch a quick
sandwich, so that I can sneak off and catch a little nap before we
get back to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x2019;ve been planting like mad for the past week, and all of this
week. Onions onions onions leeks cabbage cabbage cabbage broccoli
and other stuff I readily forget. We had a little frost scare a few
nights ago, but it never materialized. The only vulnerable thing in
the fields was the zucchini, so those got covered up for the
night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the things we&amp;#x2019;re planting were started in the greenhouse
last month. Radishes, beets, carrots, lettuce mixes, and a few
other things are all that have been directly sown. The seeder is a
mildly amusing little device that is filled with seed and run down
the beds as its wheels churn and it digs a trench, meters out seed,
fills the trench, and tamps it down. All of the rows I&amp;#x2019;ve done are
far from straight. Nobody else does much better, actually. The only
reason it matters is that it stinks when a hoe wont fit between the
two rows due to somebody&amp;#x2019;s sloppy driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2512786212.jpg" alt="Visitor from Planet Rochester"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a visitor last weekend. Rachel came out from Rochester
Thursday night via train. It was a rather nice visit, which we
started out by hand-weeding a bed of mesclun mix. That took most of
Friday actually. I milked Friday morning, just so my personal
photographer could record the event and prove that I&amp;#x2019;m on a farm
and learning things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2511952085.jpg" alt="Milking Bennie"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2511954619.jpg" alt="Milking Bennie"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x2019;re finally settling into a semi-routine as far as moving all of
the animals is concerned. We moved the chicken coop a few days ago,
and for two or three days the hens weren&amp;#x2019;t really able to find
their way back at night. So that was a chore&amp;#x2026; waiting until they
were sleeping on a fence somewhere before grabbing them and putting
them into the coop. That has finally stopped. The girl goats are
being moved to new pasture every day&amp;#x2026; boy goats every few days.
The sheep are finally out for almost a week at a time. The oxen are
chewing on possibly five days of pasture per move, but are still
being punks and getting out of their fence too often. Time to up
the voltage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2511955541.jpg" alt="Crazyface"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh! I almost forgot&amp;#x2026; we got llamas last Sunday! Llamas have a
funny looking name, and are funny looking creatures. Everything
about them is weird and they scare me and they smell and I really
really dislike them. Llamas sure do spit when agitated. And perhaps
you think &amp;#x201C;Gee Brian. Getting spit on isn&amp;#x2019;t too terrible, is
it?&amp;#x201D;&amp;#x2026; and I say yes. Yes it is, because this is llama spit and
LLAMAS DON&amp;#x2019;T BRUSH THEIR TEETH, OK? It is a foul substance that you
could only simulate by fermenting the essence of dog breath with a
touch of vomit and moldy sock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x2019;d have photos here of said llamas, but I really don&amp;#x2019;t feel like
getting my camera all smelled up. Maybe I&amp;#x2019;ll risk it soon, just so
you can see the freak show yourselves. Until then&amp;#x2026; I require
slumber.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lawnmunchers</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2008/05/lawnmunchers</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2008/05/lawnmunchers"/>
    <updated>2008-05-11T21:38:14.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2483367411.jpg" alt="Goat Runway"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when I was a youngster, I was forced to spend many hours upon
a tractor, mowing acres upon acres of foolish lawn, huffing exhaust
and damaging my hearing all the while (thanks parents!). As I sat
on my buttocks for extended periods of time, I would often set my
mind to thinking upon different fantastical technologies one could
use to trim grass with less pain and more ease. Most of what I came
up with was nebulously defined at best, but it usually involved
laser beams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes indeed. Obviously laser beams would, at the push of a button
(perhaps after turning a key or some other nuclear launch button
safety device), shoot out over your lawn at the specified height,
neatly snipping the tips of every blade in sight, perhaps even
incinerating the trimmings (if you&amp;#x2019;re the bag-em-up type). I
envisioned this system as one you would install once, with the
beams and mirrors placed in all the right spots to get behind every
tree and down into every contour of the lawn. Ever afterwards, your
juvenile life would be free of toil and full of recreation and
joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2483363581.jpg" alt="BioLawnmower Results"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now reminded of this technology every time we move the animals
and their portable electric fences. They each have their own
munching styles, but in general the combination of energized fences
and hungry hungry animals ensures a laser-like cut of grass&amp;#x2026;
every single blade right up to the fence line. When I move fence I
feel like I am setting up my childhood Lazer-Mow system, defining
the boundaries and coordinates within which the grass shall be
trimmed to my specifications. Up and down hills, over gullies,
around trees and rocks. Nothing fazes the herbivorous lawnmowing
machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2484174606.jpg" alt="BioLawnmower Results"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best of all, it&amp;#x2019;s also fertilizing the soil, reseeding the pasture,
generating meat or milk or wool or oxen-power, the only noise is
some cute bleating or the occasional moo, and it&amp;#x2019;s much less
odiferous than a tractor. It feels like a much better use of
technology, to gently guide nature with some solar powered fence
chargers and a roll of fence, instead of trying to dominate it
completely with hundreds of pounds of iron and gasoline and hours
of someone&amp;#x2019;s precious time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rainy Days</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2008/05/rainy-days</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2008/05/rainy-days"/>
    <updated>2008-05-07T22:15:21.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2460798294.jpg" alt="Farm Invasion"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I seem to keep getting yelled at for my blog inaction. I guess my
five readers are desperate for farm-based updates. This past
weekend was a rainy and semi-lazy one. It actually started on
Thursday with a rainy and cold day, which kept us inside for most
everything but the chores. It felt like a weird day of waiting to
work but not doing anything, and I got a little screwed up. It
really wasn&amp;#x2019;t a day off in my brain, but I tried to make that
mental transition, knowing that we&amp;#x2019;d have to make up time on
Saturday or Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2460803400.jpg" alt="Farm Invasion"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday was equally cold and rainy. We had a mob of children come
visit the farm, which was&amp;#x2026; entertaining. I took some photos and
then ran and hid in the barn. They appeared to enjoy seeing all of
the animals and petting lambs and whatnot. If I recall my
field-trip days though, they were probably just happy to be
outside, roughhousing and doing nothing constructive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday and Sunday continued the trend of cold and rain. We moved
animals on Sunday, just so we could say we got some durn work done
for once. Oh, and also because the oxen kept getting out of their
fence, due to the fact that they had eaten up all their pasture,
and oh look, there&amp;#x2019;s green grass right over there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh! So that&amp;#x2019;s a good story, I suppose. One of the goats was due to
kid on Friday. So after the kids (human) all left and Derek and
Maribeth left the farm to go do something, I go outside to check on
the goat and make sure there&amp;#x2019;s no signs of labor yet. But there was
a rather prominent sign, that being a baby goat on the ground,
covered in goo. Yikes! So I ran inside to tell Adam (the other
intern) and we went out and started pretending to know what we were
doing. Meanwhile Gregory from up the hill pulls into the driveway,
honking and carrying on. This is when we were notified that the
oxen were out and heading towards the garden. (!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So somehow it was decided that Adam would take care of the
midwifery and I would go pretend to be a teamster and get the oxen
back where they belong. I ran and got their leads and lickin&amp;#x2019; stick
and set off hoping for the best. I guess it&amp;#x2019;d be a better story if
there was any difficulty, but it was really absurdly easy. I&amp;#x2019;m not
sure if they&amp;#x2019;re like dogs, in that you have to sound dominant or
wrassle them and win before they listen to you&amp;#x2026; but once I got
their leads on (which is really the hardest part, but a bowl of
grain helps keep them from running away) they seemed to accept fate
and do as they were told. Luckily, I had just worked out a mnemonic
to remember the commands&amp;#x2026; gee, haw, hip, woah are the basics. Gee
means go right, and I remember that because it sounds like &amp;#x201C;get&amp;#x201D; in
the redneck accent used to yell at Rachel&amp;#x2019;s dogs, and since you
lead from the left it works out, spatially speaking. Haw is for
going left, and it reminds me of southpaw, so that&amp;#x2019;s pretty easy.
Hip is the opposite of woah, and if you don&amp;#x2019;t know woah then you&amp;#x2019;ve
never had your mom pour milk for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2459972383.jpg" alt="Guinea Egg Study"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2459974583.jpg" alt="Guinea Egg Study"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I found a Guinea egg over the weekend. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guineafowl"&gt;Guinea Fowl&lt;/a&gt; are
terrible poultry-like-objects that I&amp;#x2019;ve probably complained about
before. They make lots of noise and seem even dumber than chickens.
They hang out in the yak pen alot, and indeed that is where I found
the farm&amp;#x2019;s first Guinea Fowl egg. It&amp;#x2019;s a bit squatter and smaller
than your normal chicken egg, with a rougher shell. I failed to
photograph it whilst frying, but it had a larger yolk than one
would expect, with very little white. The yolk was very orange,
almost reddish inside, no doubt from all the god-knows-what they&amp;#x2019;re
eating out on the farm every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It tasted like any ol&amp;#x2019; egg. I found two more yesterday, and ate
those too.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Five Layer</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2008/04/five-layer</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2008/04/five-layer"/>
    <updated>2008-04-28T22:04:46.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Today was a five layer day. Shirt, thermal, hoodie, jacket, rain
coat. It has turned back into spring here, after a few weeks of
too-soon summertime. Forties and rain all day long, which will be
good for whatever we&amp;#x2019;ve gotten in the ground so far (carrots,
beets, spinach, spicy mesclun mix, other things I&amp;#x2019;ve forgotten) and
especially for the pasture, which I&amp;#x2019;m excited to see green up and
get lush and yummy looking (for a ruminant anyways). I envision it
sucking up all this rain and preparing to burst forth at the
slightest hint of sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pasture means we don&amp;#x2019;t have to feed hay twice a day, making chores
slightly quicker. For the past few weeks, chores have basically
involved bringing hay to all the animals (goats, yaks, oxen, sheep)
and making sure they have sufficient water. This happens around
seven in the morning and five in the evening. I&amp;#x2019;ve been getting the
hang of milking the goats as well, so I&amp;#x2019;m sure us interns will add
that to our routine pretty soon. It&amp;#x2019;s still new enough to be a fun
task, but already the cleanup portion of milking is a chore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x2019;ve been lax in my photo-taking lately, thus this boring and
unadorned post. I hope to rectify this soon with some panoramic
shots I&amp;#x2019;m fiddling with. Some other day though, as it is now well
past my farmer bedtime. The rain just picked up a bit, and that is
my cue to fall asleep while listening to the gutters gurgle.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Beat</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2008/04/beat</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2008/04/beat"/>
    <updated>2008-04-20T21:36:33.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x2019;s nine o&amp;#x2019;clock on a Sunday night, and I&amp;#x2019;m already considering
going to bed. This is sad not only because it&amp;#x2019;s so early, but also
because I did relatively little today. Morning and evening chores,
and that&amp;#x2019;s about it. I suppose I also rode my bike into town for
the first time, but that&amp;#x2019;s not &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt; really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was, sadly enough, a challenge though. Two and a half miles to
Ashfield proper, quite a bit of that is hill, and I am definitely
out of shape. I&amp;#x2019;m thinking it will become a good Sunday routine:
write letters all morning, ride to town and mail them, pick up some
&lt;a href="http://www.berkshirebrewingcompany.com/"&gt;beer&lt;/a&gt;, eat a slice of pizza, zip down the other side of the hill
at dangerous speeds. By the end of the summer perhaps I&amp;#x2019;ll be used
to living in an area with actual elevation changes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2419279690.jpg" alt="Spring Training"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of out of shape&amp;#x2026; last week we put the boys to work for
the first time this spring. By &amp;#x201C;we&amp;#x201D; I mean &amp;#x201C;Derek&amp;#x201D;, because there&amp;#x2019;s
no way I&amp;#x2019;ll be driving the team anytime soon, if ever. They were
especially spunky this first time out, and there was lots of
yelling and wrassling and I almost had to make a call to see if my
car insurance covers oxen damage. Luckily they stopped inches short
of my bumper, but you quickly realize that if they don&amp;#x2019;t want to do
something, such as stop or go or turn or not gore you, there&amp;#x2019;s
really not much you can do about it. But they eventually got down
to it and dragged an old tractor tire around, filled with rocks.
They got tired pretty quick, but they&amp;#x2019;ll be whipped into shape soon
enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also walked the yaks last week. That was quite the hoot. It&amp;#x2019;s
almost a good thing they&amp;#x2019;re so skittish and want to run away from
you, because I wouldn&amp;#x2019;t want them running at me. Walking the yaks
is much like walking a dog, only bigger and with horns. Once you
manage to grab one in its pen, you just clip on a leash and hold on
tight. They were pretty spunky too, as it was also their first time
out after the long winter. After a little while they settled down
and would walk by your side and heel pretty well without pulling at
the leash. I wish I had photos of that, but alas, I don&amp;#x2019;t have a
personal photographer around to take flattering pictures of me in
my new habitat.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Moving In</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2008/04/moving-in</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2008/04/moving-in"/>
    <updated>2008-04-13T11:51:28.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2409113908.jpg" alt="Moved In"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I moved into the barn yesterday, despite nighttime temperatures
that are still dipping into the mid thirties. I couldn&amp;#x2019;t resist the
draw of having my own space, and of not sleeping on the living room
couch with the family hound dog every night. It is currently forty
degrees out though, and I&amp;#x2019;m huddled up in my tent writing this. The
tent smells like camping should smell, and for now it&amp;#x2019;s a pretty
novel experience and fun to sleep in. I&amp;#x2019;m sure that will wear off.
I was plenty warm last night though, and the animals in the barn
quiet down at night, although right now they&amp;#x2019;re making quite the
racket. I&amp;#x2019;m so tired once it gets dark that I don&amp;#x2019;t think I&amp;#x2019;d
notice either way. It&amp;#x2019;s amazing how natural it is to sync up with
the daylight hours when you remove most of the artificial lighting
and electronic stimulants in your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past week has seen a variety of activities. A lot more planting
in the greenhouse. All the beds up both sides are planted with
spinach and salad mixes. The center is now packed with tables full
of seedlings, with more on the way as soon as we scrounge up more
table space (read: doors on sawhorses). Apparently we&amp;#x2019;ll be doing
weekly-or-so succession plantings of greens and such, so I&amp;#x2019;m really
interested in seeing how that is planned out and planted in order
to keep our CSA members&amp;#x2019; bags full every week. The garden at home
has lacked such a plan in the past, unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2409319424.jpg" alt="Loft View"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also cut down some dead ash trees for greenhouse fuel. We go
through quite a bit of wood at night, especially since the
greenhouse doesn&amp;#x2019;t have its second insulating plastic layer
installed. I ran a chainsaw for the first time, not cutting down
the trees but chopping the eight foot sections down into
stove-sized pieces. And then it was chopping time of course. It had
been a while, but the ash split really easily and we quickly had
enough chopped to last us a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I didn&amp;#x2019;t know what to do with the slow days, so I
ended up puttering in the greenhouse. I&amp;#x2019;m glad I did, because I got
the beds fluffed up and dried out so we could plant earlier&amp;#x2026; but
this weekend I&amp;#x2019;m definitely more comfortable with just taking a
break. I&amp;#x2019;m looking forward to warm days off when I can go explore
the area on my bike. I hear there are waterfalls and wading pools
nearby!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Stimulating Activities</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2008/04/stimulating-activities</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2008/04/stimulating-activities"/>
    <updated>2008-04-07T23:16:40.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2397703260.jpg" alt="Wee Sheep"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been reprimanded for not posting enough, and for not taking
enough pictures of baby animals. One of those &amp;#x201C;problems&amp;#x201D; is easy to
remedy. As you may be noticing, this post is awash in photographs
of cute baby sheep and goats and even a bad puppy. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2397696690.jpg" alt="Wee Sheep"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2397689766.jpg" alt="Wee Sheep"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as writing more, I suppose I&amp;#x2019;ll have to just write about the
minute doings of my current life. I guess maybe that&amp;#x2019;s interesting.
Today, I drove a tractor. A tractor with a bucket thingy and
separate pedals for forward and reverse, and separate left and
right brakes. It seems like a really good idea to me, to have four
pedals available for maximizing your messing up potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the tractor to do two things: After we mucked out all the
stalls this morning, I had to scrape the bedding away from the barn
and scoop it into the big steamy pile of cow goo. I feel like the
bucket control lever could have a much more intuitive interface
(perhaps a scroll wheel or a trackpad?) but I managed to get the
hang of it just fine. In the afternoon I had to take water up to
the oxen, who are out on pasture finally (they were very happy to
be out of the barn, and I wish I had shot video of the terrifying
sight of a 1600 pound oxen jumping and bucking with glee whilst
stumbling down the hillside towards the tiny yet apparently
effective portable electric fencing). This involves filling a basin
and toting it up the hill in the tractor&amp;#x2019;s bucket, whilst not
spilling too much. I got it all the way up the hill, and dropped it
as I was setting it down inside the fence. Round two was more
successful, with the boys receiving not only fifteen gallons of
water, but also their surprisingly heavy mineral block for licking
upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2396852459.jpg" alt="Bad Dog"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2396850507.jpg" alt="Wee Goat"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It only took two days for me to get zapped by the aforementioned
fencing. It felt similar to when I plugged in my Lite-Brite
incorrectly (read: while squeezing the prongs together to fit it in
the outlet), only this time no thoughts of turning into a robot
crossed my mind, and I find that terribly disappointing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Arrival</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2008/04/arrival</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2008/04/arrival"/>
    <updated>2008-04-04T10:56:26.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2386691326.jpg" alt="The Barn++"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry for the delay&amp;#x2026; I arrived on the farm Tuesday and have been
rather busy since. I just got a chance to set up the internets last
night. I also haven&amp;#x2019;t taken a ton of photos yet, I feel like a
tourist boob whipping out my camera at every single interesting
thing. I&amp;#x2019;ve certainly missed a lot of cute baby photo-ops thus far
(cute animal babies, that is). Just yesterday there was some
feeding of a newborn lamb in the house next to the fire. It was the
only one of five to survive, so a sad morning, but happy that this
one pulled through and got up on its wobbly too-big legs and is now
back in the barn nursing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2386687502.jpg" alt="A Field, Plus Jebedaiah"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The area is beautiful, even when it&amp;#x2019;s all melty and muddy. Last
night we got a dusting of snow, so it&amp;#x2019;s back to a lovely winter
white, if you&amp;#x2019;re into that sort of thing. Personally, I&amp;#x2019;m rather
done with winter and am looking forward to seeing this place put on
some fuzzy green pantaloons. We were working in the greenhouse
yesterday, and will do so again today. It was one-hundred degrees
in there when we opened the doors&amp;#x2026; rather nice to work in short
sleeves and sweat a bit, although my back is sore from preparing
the beds for planting greens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to feed the fire in the greenhouse a couple of times a
night, and my shifts are gradually getting later and later as I am
less and less the new guy. I hope the nights warm up soon, so we
can all get uninterrupted sleep again. Even with the slumbertime
chores I&amp;#x2019;m finding it pretty easy to get up around six or so. That
might be because things wind down here around ten and I find it
hard to stay up much later than that. Certainly is a schedule
shift, and I&amp;#x2019;m struggling to figure out how to separate free-time
from work-time and how to relax and also get other personal
projects done. Today we&amp;#x2019;re taking a wee break before going out to
work. Everybody is gone but Adam (the other intern) and I.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, it&amp;#x2019;s almost the top of the hour, time to check on the
soon-to-be-mother sheep and get down to work. Expect more bland
stories and flaccid insight in the weeks to come!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Gone Farmin'</title>
    <id>https://boucheron.org/2008/04/gone-farmin</id>
    <link href="https://boucheron.org/2008/04/gone-farmin"/>
    <updated>2008-04-01T07:56:19.000Z</updated>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;As most of you know, I have left the lovely village of Rochester
for a few months, in order to more fully scratch an itch I&amp;#x2019;ve been
having regarding food and agriculture and ecology and so on. I&amp;#x2019;ll
be working on a wee family farm in Ashfield, Massachusetts until
mid-October. I am fully prepared for this to be a slightly
different work experience than my previous job as a chair-sloucher
and mouse-pusher, and am looking forward to that. I hope to
experience 110% more sunshine, 80% more animal dander, and 1254%
more plant matter than in previous years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to more gently ease into the great outdoors, I went to
Mendon Ponds park on Sunday with some of my most special Rochester
friends. We experienced &amp;#x201C;nature&amp;#x201D; by walking through its
well-groomed paths and feeding the ferociously wild Chickadees out
of our bare hands. No doubt these skills will come in handy when
dealing with the various domesticated fowl on the farm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2375384241.jpg" alt="Avian Adventure"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/brian/img/2376226798.jpg" alt="Avian Adventure"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x2019;m currently at my parent&amp;#x2019;s house in Floyd, eating some niblets in
preparation for more travel. I&amp;#x2019;ve got about three hours of driving
left, hopefully with a stop in the middle to check out Troy and its
curious inhabitants. I&amp;#x2019;m not sure what to expect upon arrival
at&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href="http://sanghafarm.com/" title="The Sangha Farm Website"&gt;Sangha Farm&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;this afternoon. I visited them of course, and it
seemed really great. I&amp;#x2019;m just bracing for it to be a big change of
pace in so many ways.&amp;#xA0;But, I&amp;#x2019;m excited and ready to get down to it.
Keep an eye out for a plentitude of photos and more blathering&amp;#x2026;
soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>